Guide to the Forest Hills Gardens (New York, N.Y.) Records, 1900-1970, 1911-1919 (bulk)
Forest Hills Gardens (New York, N.Y.) Records, 1900-1970, 1911-1919 (bulk)
- I-F 514, 1915 (Map-case Folder 33)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Plumbing Section, Front Entrance Elevation, Front Entrance details, Garage - 2 Preliminary Sketches, Details of Terrace Steps
  Other Details: 34 Greenway South
- I-F 514 (second version), 1915 (Map-case Folder 33)
  Drawings List: Grade Plan, Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Left Side Elevation
- I-F 534 thr I-F 542, 1915 (Map-case Folder 34)
  Project Description: Houses Group No XXXVII
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Front Porch, Side Elevation, Plumbing Section
- I-F 544, 1915 (Map-case Folder 35)
  Project Description: House for Ward J. McNeal, M. D.
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, West Elevation, East Elevation, South Elevation, Garage
- I-F 545, 1915 (Map-case Folder 35)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. Rheta Childs Dorr
  Drawings List: Foundation Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Left Side Elevation
- I-F 548, 1915 (Map-case Folder 36)
  Project Description: Cottage for Mrs. Ellen B. Kendall
  Architect: Fred J. Sterner, Architect
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Markwood Elevation, Rock Rose Place Elevation, West Elevation, South Elevation, Transverse Section, Longitudinal Section
  Other Details: 31 Markwood Road
- I-F 595, 1912 (Map-case Folder 36)
  Project Description: House for J. M. Demarest, Esq.
  Drawings List: Preliminary Sketches: 5 plates - First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation; Blueprints: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Side Elevations, Rear Elevation
- I-F 600, 1915 (Map-case Folder 37)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Plumbing Section
- I-F 614, 1915 (Map-case Folder 37)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. A. H. Smith
  Architect: Oswald C. Hering and Douglas C. Fitch
  Drawings List: Foundation Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, East Elevation, North Elevation, South Elevation, West Elevation
- I-F 619, 1915-1916 (Map-case Folder 38)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation
- I-F 630, 1916 (Map-case Folder 38)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. Feangio G. Robinson
  Architect: J. Elleck, Architect
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan
- I-F 631, 1916-1917 (Map-case Folder 38)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. W. P. Beazell
  Architect: Aymar Embury II, Architect
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, South Elevation, End Elevation, North Elevation, Details of Interiors
- I-F 649, I-F 653, 1916 (Map-case Folder 39)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Plumbing Section, Scale Elevation
- I-F 665 & I-F 666, 1916 (Map-case Folder 39)
  Project Description: Company Houses
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Cross Section, Longitudinal Section
- I-F 667, 1916 (Map-case Folder 40)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Cross Section, Longitudinal Section
- I-F 669, 1916 (Map-case Folder 40)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Plumbing Section, Cross Section
  Other Details: dated revisions
- I-F 702, 1916-1917 (Map-case Folder 41)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Garage and Bicycle Room Elevation Plate
  Other Details: 19 Winter Street, nothing for property plot. dated revisions
- I-F 748, 1918 (Map-case Folder 41)
  Project Description: Residence for Henry Hirschberg, Esq.
  Architect: Alfred Fellheimer
  Drawings List: Block Plan, Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Puritan Avenue Elevation, East Elevation, West Elevation, South Elevation
- I-F 749, 1917-1918 (Map-case Folder 42)
  Project Description: House for Basil D'Emo, Esq.
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, Continental Avenue Elevation, South East Elevation, Side Elevation, Key to Groups in Block 25, Key to Groups in Block 20
- I-F 800, 1918 (Map-case Folder 42)
  Project Description: Garage for Chas. Bishop, Esq.
- I-F 905 & I-F 906, 1919 (Map-case Folder 43)
  Project Description: House for Adam Reinhart
  Architect: George Woehrlin, Architect
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Side Elevation
- I-F 930, 931, 932 & 933, 1919 (Map-case Folder 44)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Section, Plumbing Section
- I-F 932 (Map-case Folder 44)
  Project Description: Group 55 - House
  Drawings List: Second Floor Plan, Rear Elevation
- I-F 935, 1919 (Map-case Folder 45)
  Project Description: House for J. B. Reimer
  Architect: F. G. Lippert
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, South Elevation, West Elevation, North Elevation, East Elevation
- I-F 937, 1919 (Map-case Folder 45)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Front Elevation
- I-F 939, 1919 (Map-case Folder 46)
  Project Description: Residence for George A. Douglass
  Architect: Williams & Mahnken, Architects
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, 2 plates: Elevation from Groton Street and Elevation from Continental Avenue
- I-F 939, 1919 (Map-case Folder 46)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. George A. Douglass
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Front Elevation, Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Sections of Interiors, Details
- I-F 941, 1919 (Map-case Folder 46)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. Margaret A. Farmer
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Plumbing Section
- I-F 948, 1919-1920 (Map-case Folder 47)
  Project Description: Reutermann
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Basement Floor Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Side Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Garage Rear Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Section
- I-F 949, 1919 (Map-case Folder 47)
  Project Description: Residence for Howard A. Darrin
  Architect: L. Allen. E. Bling, Hugo, E. Magnuson
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, North West Elevation, South East Elevation, Cross Section, Interior Elevation, Trim Details
- I-F 954, 1919 (Map-case Folder 48)
  Project Description: House for John M. Kinney
  Architect: George Keister, Architect
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, Different Elevations
- I-F 1018, 1920 (Map-case Folder 48)
  Project Description: House for Mrs. Chas. Plummer
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Front Elevation, Plumbing Section
- I-F 1020, Undated (Map-case Folder 49)
  Project Description: Residence of F. E. Smith, Esq.
  Architect: Touchstone Architectural Department
  Drawings List: Preliminary Sketches, Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation
  Other Details: Multiple copies of some drawings, Note in Finding aid {Note: these comprise a set of pencil drawings (6 items) and blueprints of same (6 items), all stamped "To Be Returned to Grosvenor Atterbury….". Also, one blue print of a rather rough drawing of what appears to be the main floor; this is the only item marked "Touchstone". - kj, 5/7/80}
- I-F 1022, 1920 (Map-case Folder 49)
  Architect: Timmis & Chapman
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, West Elevation, East Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Dormer Windows Front Elevation, Cross Section looking North
- I-F 1023 & I-F 1024, 1920 (Map-case Folder 50)
  Project Description: Two Family House for W. T. Anderson
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Front Elevation, South Elevation, East Elevation, Cross Section
- I-F 1024, Undated (Map-case Folder 50)
  Drawings List: Bay Windows Extension
- I-F 1031-1036, 1920 (Map-case Folder 51)
  Project Description: Houses - Group 60
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, Party Line Garage - I-F 1036&1037, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Roof Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Plumbing Section
  Other Details:
- I-F 1037, (I-F 1040 reversed), c. 1920 (Map-case Folder 52)
  Project Description: House - Group 61
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, Basement Floor Plan of 1040, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Elevation, Rear Elevation, Left Side Elevation of 1037, Plumbing Section
- I-F 1038 & I-F 1039, 1920 (Map-case Folder 52)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Roof Plan of 1039, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Plumbing Section
- I-F 1072, 1921 (Map-case Folder 53)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Roof Plan
- I-F 1072- I-F 1075, 1921 (Map-case Folder 53)
  Project Description: House for Mr. Roberts
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Front Elevation: 1072-1075, Rear Elevation: 1073-1075, Left Elevation: 1073, Garage all elevations, House 1075 - (Bruce)
- I-F 1073 & I-F 1074, 1921 (Map-case Folder 53)
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan
- I-F 1080, 1921 (Map-case Folder 54)
  Project Description: Winifred M. Allwork
  Architect: Allwork & Woehrlin
- I-F 1103, Undated (Map-case Folder 54)
  Project Description: Residence for Walter Burden, Esq.
  Architect: William A. Parfitt
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Front Elevations, Rear Elevation, Side Elevation, Section, Section on A.A.
  Other Details: Multiple copies of some drawings, Located at NW corner of Greenway South and Summer Street
- I-F 1105, Undated (Map-case Folder 55)
  Project Description: House for E. C. Stokes
  Architect: George J. Woehrlin
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Roof Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Side Elevation, Plumbing Plan, Plumbing Section, Heating Plan, Details for Doors and Windows, Riser Schedule
- I-F 1106, Undated (Map-case Folder 55)
  Architect: Stowe Phelps & John Tompkins
  Drawings List: First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, Greenway South Elevation, Groton Elevation, 1/2 Front Elevation, 1/2 Side Elevation, West Elevation, South Elevation
  Other Details: Located at Greenway South and Groton Streets
- (Map-case Folder)
  Drawings List:
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Apartment #1
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Apartment #2
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Streets
  Other Details: Block Plan of Streets
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Drawings List: Diagram of Property - Block Plan
- No I-F Number, 1910 (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Group III
- No I-F Number, 1910 (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Group VI "A"
- No I-F Number, 1910 (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Group VI "B"
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Group XIX
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: 3 Single-Family Houses
  Drawings List: Block Plan, North Elevation
  Other Details: Note: Use for Scribner Magazine, July 1912
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: R. R. Station & Shelters
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: Hotels 4 & 5
  Other Details: Showing Location of Hotels 4 & 5
- No I-F Number, 1922 (Map-case Folder 59)
  Project Description: Slocum Crescent Homes, Inc., Owners 358 5th Avenue, New York
  Drawings List: Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Burns Street Elevation, Slocum Crescent bldg. - Rear Elevation, Front Elevation; Burns Street bldg. - South Elevation, North Elevation, Bye Street bldg. - Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, Elevations - Holder Place, Garden, Slocum Crescent, Vestibule Entrance; South Elevation of Court, Middlemay Circle Elevation, North Elevation
- No I-F Number, 1910, Undated (Map-case Folder 67)
  Project Description: West Side of Continental Avenue
  Other Details: 2 plates
- No I-F Number, 1916-1919 (Map-case Folder 60)
  Project Description: House for Harvey Warren, Esq.
  Architect: Wm Lawrence Bottomley
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Basement Floor Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, West Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Garage
- No I-F Number, 1911 (Map-case Folder 61)
  Project Description: House A, Group XIV
  Architect: Aymar Embury, II
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation
- No I-F Number, 1911 (Map-case Folder 61)
  Project Description: A & B, Group XIV
  Drawings List: Details Window Frames First and Second Story Walls, Interior and Exterior Details
- No I-F Number, 1911 (Map-case Folder 61)
  Project Description: House B, Group XIV
- No I-F Number, 1914 (Map-case Folder 62)
  Project Description: Residence for Chas. Robinson Smith, Esq.
  Architect: Peabody - Wilson & Brown
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Attic Plan, West Elevation, East Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Elevation of Veranda, Details of Entrance Doorway, Details of Cornice
- No I-F Number, 1921 (Map-case Folder 62)
  Project Description: Residence for P. J. Maloney, Esq.
  Architect: W. H. Rahmann & Sons
  Drawings List: Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Rear Elevation, South Elevation, North Elevation, Longitudinal Section, Transverse Section
- No I-F Number, 1959 (Map-case Folder 63)
  Project Description: House for Mr. & Mrs. Emil Lence
  Architect: Edwin Storde
  Drawings List: Plot Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Front Elevation, Left Side Elevation, Rear Elevation, Right Side Elevation, Section, Plumbing Section, Details of Cesspool, Drywell, Fireplace details, Front Porch Details
  Other Details: Multiple copies of some drawings, Proposed New House in 1959, includes Specifications, Correspondence and Memos
- No I-F Number, 1919 (Map-case Folder 64)
  Drawings List: Elevation on Burns Street, Elevation on Tennis Place. Court Elevation, South End Elevation, East End Elevation, Part of Block 14
  Other Details: Apartment House corner of Burns Street and Tennis Place
- No I-F Number, 1919-1921 (Map-case Folder 65)
  Project Description: Gardens Apartments
  Drawings List: Typical Floor Plans, Basement Floor Plan, Cellar Plan, First Floor Plan, Second Floor Plan, Third Floor Plan, Fourth Floor Plan, Fifth Floor Plan, Roof Plan, Burns Street Elevation, Tennis Place Elevation, Court Elevation, East Elevation, South Elevation, Section Looking North, Section Looking East, Study of Railings Between Gables and Tennis Place, Key to Groups in Block 20 and 25
- No I-F Number, Undated (Map-case Folder 66)
  Project Description: House for F. G, Wheeler, Esq.
  Architect: Architect Unknown
  Drawings List: Front Elevation, Side Elevation
- No I-F Number, 1915 (Map-case Folder 66)
  Project Description: L. Atshaw House & F. S. Wheeler House
  Drawings List: First Floor Plan
- No number, Undated (Map-case Folder 68)
  Project Description: Forest Hills Gardens
  Drawings List: 3 Maps
  Other Details: Miscellaneous, Title: Forest Hills, The Garden Spot of L. I. as seen by Charlie Seewald; Street map: "Map Number 5, surveyed for the Sage Foundation Homes Company, July 1918 (photocopies of a map from collection #2775)
- No number, Undated (Map-case Folder 68)
  Drawings List: Maps
  Other Details: Street map: "Map Number 5, surveyed for the Sage Foundation Homes Company, July 1918 (photocopies of a map from collection #2775)
- No number, Undated (Map-case Folder 68)
  Drawings List: 2 Maps
  Other Details: Title: Forest Hills, Gateway to World's Fair as seen by Eric Sloane
- No number, Undated (Map-case Folder 69)
  Project Description: Forest Hills Garden
  Drawings List: Informational guide to Forest Hill Gardens